PRASANNA BAJRA BAJRACHARYA

Associate Team Lead | Software Engineer | Freelancer

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and service industry. Skilled in SQL, Web applications, Window services and ASP.NET MVC. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Information Technology, BSc. CSIT from Tribhuvan University.

✓ prasbuzz15@gmail.com

9841658101

Swoyambhu, Kathmandu, Nepal

prasannabajracharya.com.np

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To work in a dynamic professional environment with a growing organization, also utilize my skills of software design/development, database development and project management for the benefit of the organization, IT/service industry and myself.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Team Lead 2017 - 2018

ebPearls Pty. Ltd, Lalitpur, Nepal

- Take ownership of project in terms of quality and timely wise delivery.
- Conduct risk analysis and identify potential risks and challenges in the project.
- Understand the project requirements clearly.
- Generate queries in case there is any confusion in understanding the project.
- Discuss any technical challenges that might come while working on the project.
- Realize the project delivery date and understand the communication channels.
- Set coding standard of the project and maintain efficient, reusable and reliable code.
- Conduct first hand testing of the project tasks before submitting.
- Check feedback from clients and identify bugs and request for change accordingly.
- Co-ordinate with and report to Team Leader/Project Manager/Clients

Senior Software Engineer

2016 - 2017

ebPearls Pty. Ltd, Lalitpur, Nepal

- Requirement gathering and risk analysis
- Project/Task discussion and estimation
- Software/Web development for new and ongoing projects
- Design, build and maintain efficient, reusable and reliable code
- Interaction with team members/clients
- Timely project delivery
- Provide technical assistance to team members
- Co-ordinate with and report to Team Leader/Project Manager

Software Engineer 2012 - 2016

ebPearls Pty. Ltd, Lalitpur, Nepal

- Requirement gathering and risk analysis
- Project/Task discussion and estimation
- Software/Web development for new and ongoing projects
- Code refactoring and optimization, perform test cases and bug fixing
- Interaction with team members/clients

- Timely project delivery
- Co-ordinate with and report to Team Leader/Project Manager

Intern 2012

Nepal Telecommunications Authority, Lalitpur, Nepal

- Worked on log monitoring module for ADSL system
- Use of technologies such as HTML, CSS, PHP and MySQL
- Design, develop, implement and test the system
- Write bash script for maintenance and transfer of log files
- Prepare report on the development process of the system
- Co-ordinate with and report to Team Leader/Project Manager

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Markup Languages HTML, CSS, XML, XSLT, AJAX, JSON Scripting Languages Javascript, JQuery, PHP, AngularJS

Programming Languages C, C++, C#, SQL

Software Frameworks .NET, ASP.NET MVC, Web Services, Window Services

Database Management Tools MySQL, SQLyog, PostgreSQL, MS-SQL, Oracle Visual Studio IDE, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text

Version Control Tools Visual Studio Team Services, Team Foundation Server, GIT

Web Server Tools IIS, Apache HTTP Server CMS Frameworks DotNetNuke, Umbraco Project Management Tools Zoho, Basecamp, Jira

Graphic Applications Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom
Microsoft Office Packages Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Access, Outlook

Basic Computer Skills Desktop Publishing, Email & Internet

PROJECTS

Crewgo | www.crewgo.co

Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, ASP C#.NET Web API, MySQL, MS-SQL 2016, Hangfire

Yetimo | www.yetimo.com

Javascript, HTML, CSS, ASP C#.NET Webforms, MS-SQL 2012

Deep East Music | www.deepeastmusic.com

AngularJS, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP C#.NET MVC

Hello Pojo | www.hellopojo.com

AngularJS, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP C#.NET MVC

West One Music | www.westonemusic.com

AngularJS, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP C#.NET MVC

Video Helper www.videohelper.com

AngularJS, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP C#.NET MVC

Big Bang Fuzz | www.bigbangfuzz.com

AngularJS, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP C#.NET MVC

Stairtek Quote Tool | www.stairtekquote.com

AngularJS, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3, ASP C#.NET Webforms

TRAININGS

Managerial Skills	2017
Managerial Skills	201

ebPearls Pty. Ltd, Lalitpur, Nepal

.NET Programming 2012

Kathford International College of Engineering & Management, Lalitpur, Nepal

Diploma in Web Designing & Programming

Alliance International Inc., Kathmandu, Nepal

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science & Information Technology, BSc. CSIT

Kathford International College of Engineering & Management, Lalitpur, Nepal

Affiliated to Tribhuvan University, Kirtipur, Nepal

Higher Secondary Education Board, HSEB

National Institute of Technical Sciences, Kathmandu, Nepal

School Leaving Certificate, SLC

Swarnim School, Kathmandu, Nepal

REFERENCES

Mr. Rupesh Rajopadhyaya

Senior Project Manager

ebPearls Pty. Ltd

Kupondole, Lalitpur, Nepal

E-mail: raj.rupesh@gmail.com

Contact: 9851-168910

Mr. Ishwor Dangol

Product & Project Manager

Braindigit IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Gyaneshwor, Kathmandu, Nepal

2005

2011

2007

2003

E-mail: gishwor@gmail.com

Contact: 9841-466590